https://www.abacusemedia.com/privacy-policy-and-terms-of-use/

By continuing to use this site you agree to our cookies policy:
Insights
Webvision Cloud – Improving Engagement and Revenue Opportunities at MBI
Royal Society of Chemistry: Opening the doors to non-members
Markets
Media & PublishingOur solutions help publishers develop and monetise their content and products while maximising audience engagement. Our content management and audience management technology gives content owners the agility and flexibility they need to run successful digital content operations.
Media & Publishing
Member BodiesOur solutions help member bodies to be member focused in an increasingly competitive market. Our technology and services enable you to increase member engagement and revenue by delivering valuable member experiences through relevant content delivery and personalised member communications.
Member Bodies
BrandsOur solutions help brands and communities delight their customers with tailored digital experiences. Our technology and services enable Charities, Retail and Financial Services organisations to increase customer engagement and revenue with targeted offers and relevant content driven by powerful insights combining data from multiple channels.
BRANDS
Platforms
Digital eXperience PlatformWebvision Cloud is a GDPR-compliant Digital eXperience Platform (DXP), comprising a professional mobile-friendly website, an enterprise-class CMS and a market-leading audience engagement database – all in the cloud. The hierarchical preference centre (Compliance Hub) keeps track of all interactions with your customers so that your organisation can demonstrate lawful consent and ongoing engagement (for legitimate interest).
Webvision Cloud
Customer Data PlatformThe ADvance SaaS customer data platform (CDP) is a GDPR-compliant multichannel single customer view, customer identity & access management (CIAM) and e-commerce system in one. Combining data from multiple sources allows powerful insights and segmentation to drive dynamically personalised offers and experiences, improving customer engagement and propensity to buy.
ADvance
Customers
PublishersWe help deliver sophisticated digital products and solutions to the publishing industry
Member bodiesWe provide digital products & services to member organisations & associations
E-commerceWe provide an elegant online buying experience for content owners
Insights
Webvision Cloud – Improving Engagement and Revenue Opportunities at MBI
Royal Society of Chemistry: Opening the doors to non-members
Christie’s: Worldwide subscription and catalogue management
Royal Pharmaceutical Society: The search for relevance
Blog
News, Opinions & Blog
Customer experience management
Content management
Audience engagement
Digital strategy
Corporate subscriptions
Member engagement
Consultancy
Subscribe
Let’s Get Digital!
The digital revolution has brought about a new type of customer – the ‘digital consumer’. And the rapid rise of the digital consumer has changed the faces of many industries and is creating pressure on businesses to transform their strategies and operations to meet the changing needs of their customers.
MGP wins at the PPA Independent Publishing Awards
Webvision Cloud client MGP continues to prove the strength of the platform, taking home Independent Publishing Company of the Year – Congratulations!
PPA Independent Awards 2020 shortlist announced
The prestigious awards celebrate the individuals, brands, and content owners driving the magazine and business media industry’s ongoing digital revolution. We are delighted that our clients have been shortlisted for top industry awards.
Services
Digital Transformation ConsultancyWe’ve created a team of highly specialised consultants with unrivalled experience in developing all aspects of online strategy – many with proven track records of building successful digital businesses themselves. Our services include: Digital Commercial Strategy, Content and Production Strategy, Subscription and Renewals Marketing Strategy, Site Optimisation Strategy, and Systems Integration Consultancy
Consultancy Services
Bureau ServicesAbacus’s bureau services operation, also known as ADvance Services, offers clients an end-to-end subscription management and fulfilment services capability underpinned by a modern day e-commerce platform, that is configured to allow clients to ‘pick and mix’ the services they wish to use. Our range of services are designed to help media owners grow their audience, and deliver real value for their businesses.
Bureau Services
Company
About Us
Insights
Integrations
Help Centre
Awards
Press
Contact Us
GDPR
GDPRStay on the right side of the new regulations and implement engagement strategies that foster trust and business growth
Learn More
Privacy Policy & Terms of Use
Abacus is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of site visitors, prospects, and customers. We will not sell personal information to anyone and information captured on this site will be processed and utilised only by Abacus within the UK.
The purpose of this policy is to explain the types of information we obtain from users through the Abacus website and other channels, how the information is obtained, how it is used, how it may be obtained by others, and how its use and disclosure can be restricted.
Abacus may change this policy from over time by updating this page. This policy is effective from 22/02/2018.
Legal basis for processing data
According to the definition of the ICO, Abacus is a private sector organisation (all for-profit business). Abacus utilises the lawful basis of Legitimate Interests under GDPR to process data and send out direct marketing communications under PECR/e-Privacy. Our business model relies on selling our products and services to other businesses to improve their customer engagement and so our marketing activity is potentially mutually beneficial. Email is our main form of marketing activity, and we provide an unsubscribe link for corporate individuals to opt-out/object to the further processing of their data should they so choose. We also use direct telesales, through which we allow the individual to reserve the right to notify us to not call them again. We only market to businesses and persons within those businesses that we genuinely believe would be interested in our products and services.
The ICO states that ‘Direct marketing covers the promotion of aims and ideals as well as the sale of products and services,’ and GDPR states that ‘the processing of personal data for direct marketing purposes may be regarded as carried out for a legitimate interest.’
Abacus has conducted a Legitimate Interests Assessment (LIA) Test which has identified the relevant legitimate interests and deemed it the most appropriate legal basis for our marketing activities. We have conducted a balancing test and are confident that our target individual’s interests do not override those legitimate interests. This has all been documented to justify our decision. We will keep our LIA under regular review and repeat both the assessment and balancing tests if our circumstances change.
Regarding current clients using our platforms and services, Abacus utilises the lawful basis of Contractual Obligations to send regular updates via email communications. This includes monthly release notes, support updates and any other relevant communications to their terms of use.
Data we collect
The main information we initially collect is name, job title, email address, and phone number. Abacus may use this information to make contact to further discuss (possible) interest in our company, platforms, and services.
Those that complete the Demo Request, Contact Us and/or Webinar Video forms agree that they are authorising Abacus to contact them regarding their enquiry and to be added to our marketing mailing list about our products and services. They can opt out of being further contacted by us by using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails or contacting us at marketing@abacusemedia.com.
Use of IP Tracking
We currently use IP tracking technology (Google Analytics and Salesforce Pardot) to identify businesses visiting our site and the pages that are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic in order to develop and improve our website for business visitors. It also helps us determine who is interested in our platforms and services and gives us better insight into how we might be able to provide a solution to their business.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, visitors who use these links to leave our site should note that we do not have any control over those other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information provided whilst visiting such sites as they are not governed by this privacy policy. Visitors should exercise caution and review the privacy policy applicable to the website in question.
Abacus is not responsible for the content of external internet sites.
Disclosure
Abacus will not sell individual information to any third parties. Abacus does not disclose personal information to third parties, except as set forth in this policy and in cases where Abacus, acting in good faith, believes that such action is necessary to conform to legal requirements or comply with a legal process, such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order.
Some frequently asked privacy questions
What are cookies?
Cookies are files of information that a website stores on a computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make the web more useful by storing information about visitor preferences on a particular site. Cookies allow websites to ‘remember’ users across pages of a site and across multiple visits to a site. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and many major websites use them to provide useful features to their visitors. Cookies, in and of themselves, do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user’s computer. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. Cookies cannot damage user files, nor can they read unrelated information from a user’s hard drive. Users may set their browser settings to refuse cookies, though this may affect website functionality and performance.
Is my personal information secure?
The personal information collected by Abacus is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the general public. Abacus follows information security policies in accordance with ISO27001. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, while we strive to protect all personal information, Abacus cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us over the internet.
We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time.
Any questions regarding this privacy policy should be directed to webmaster@abacusemedia.com.
We’d love to hear from you...
ABOUT USPRESSCAREERSPRIVACY POLICY & TERMS OF USEModern Slavery StatementCONTACT USINSIGHTSCOOKIE POLICYSITE MAPHelp Centre
